Guide to the Time Inc. International Records 1957-1974, 1984-1997 MS 3009-RG 56
New-York Historical Society
Time Inc. International Records
1957-1974, 1984-1997
New-York Historical Society
Time, inc.
MS 3009-RG 56
8 Linear feet in 8 record cartons.
Time Inc. International marketed and published Time Inc. magazines outside the United States. It set up offices in various cities around the world to work on regional version of magazines, made deals to license the names of Time Inc. magazines to foreign publishers, and occasionally published original magazines in foreign territories. The collection consists of correspondence, reports, data on sales and expenses, projections and propositions for the future, and printed presentations. This record group includes files from earlier divisions that provided the same function such as Time Life International (TLI) and Corporate International.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are stored offsite and advance notice is required for use. Please contact manuscripts@nyhistory.org prior to your research visit to coordinate access. Keep in mind that it will take between two (2) and five (5) business days for collections to arrive, and you should plan your research accordingly.
Open to qualified researchers with the exception of restricted materials. Restricted materials include contracts and employees' personal information. Restricted materials are located in box R86.
Arrangement
The materials within the Time Inc. International Files record group are organized into three series: I. International Offices Files; III. Vice President Martin Gardner Files; and III. Mike Taylor Files.
Historical Note
Time Life International was responsible for the sale of Time Inc. magazines outside the United States. This included setting up offices in cities around the world and establishing communications between this foreign offices and Time Inc. headquarters in New York City and printing and shipping versions of American magazines (such as Time ) tailored for specific regions around the world. Time Inc. headquarters retained significant control over foreign offices in terms of editorial, hiring, changes in pay and benefits for employees, and purchasing of office space and equipment. Between 1967 and 1968 the name of the division was changed to Corporate International, but seems to have retained the same staff and functions. Later, a division called Time Inc. International handled these same functions, suggesting the latter is the same division after another name change, but there is not direct evidence for this in the collection.
In addition to the functions described above, Time Inc. International also made deals with foreign publishers to license the names of Time Inc. magazines such as Fortune; such operations were governed by agreements regarding content and style but not under the direct control of Time Inc. Time Inc. International also published original magazines in foreign countries such as Who Weekly in Australia.
Provenance
Gift of Time Inc. in 2015.
Related Materials
This finding aid relates to just one record group of the Time Inc. Records. For information about the other record groups and for overall information about the archives, please see the Guide to the Time Inc. Records (MS 3009). The Henry Luce Papers (MS 3014) were acquired with the Time Inc. Records. The collection of books acquired with the records are cataloged as the Time Inc. Reference Library.
Some records from TLI Managing Director Charles Bear and his assistant Howard Dunn are in Bear's files in the Office of the Vice President of Administration and International Files in the Time Inc. Corporate Administation Records (MS 3009-RG 5).
The Time Inc. Annex Files (MS 3009-RG 39) contain further information about international business and international editions of various Time Inc. magazines.
The Edgar R. Baker Papers (MS 3156) document his tenure as head of Time-Life International from the mid-1940s to the mid-1960s and changes in the division during that time.
Scope and Contents
Part of the collection contains records using the name Time Life International and part contains records using the name Time Inc. International. See the Historical Note for more information. During the time span represented by their files in the collection, Martin Gardner was Vice President of Time Inc. International and Mike Taylor worked on "strategic aspects of international magazine publishing" according to his LinkedIn profile viewed in 2021.
The collection consists of correspondence, reports and information on ad sales, subscriptions, and expenses for Time Inc. International Magazines, discussion of pay and benefits for employees, assessments of the states of publishing ventures and proposals for future action, budgets, and samples of magazines.
Corporations -- History; Corporations -- New York (State) -- New York; Corporation records; International business enterprises.; Organization files; Publishers and publishing -- New York (State) -- New York; Publishers and publishing -- Management; Time, inc. -- Archives; Time, inc. -- History; Time, inc. -- Management
- Series I: International Offices Files, 1957-1974; 2 Linear feet in 2 record cartons.
  Scope and Contents
  Series I consists of correspondence, reports on business conditions in foreign countries, and data on sales, subscriptions, and expenses for Time Inc. international magazines. Most of the folders are organized into "business" and "personnel" for different cities in which Time Inc. offices are located; the former regarding general business operations and the latter regarding issues of hiring, pay, and benefits for employees. Common correspondents include Charles B. Bear, Vice President of Time Life International during the time these files were created, his assistants, Charles Terranella, Paul Hale, and Howard Dunn, and J. Winston Fowlkes, Business Manager of Time Life International and later of Corporate-International.
  Arrangement
  Series I is arranged alphabetically.
  - Asia: Miscellaneous, 1967-1969 (Offsite-box 4187, Folder 1)
  - Germany: Office Equipment, 1960-1967 (Offsite-box 4187, Folder 2)
  - Hong Kong, 1969 (Offsite-box 4187, Folder 3)
  - India: Legal, 1969-1971 (Offsite-box 4187, Folder 4)
  - Japan: Bank Accounts, 1968-1969 (Offsite-box 4187, Folder 5)
  - Japan: Monthly Updaters, 1973-1974 (Offsite-box 4187, Folder 6)
  - Japan: Personnel Policy Manual, 1957-1964 (Offsite-box 4187, Folder 7)
  - Latin/South America: Miscellaneous, 1968-1970 (Offsite-box 4187, Folder 8)
  - Life: International Reduction, 1970-1971 (Offsite-box 4187, Folder 9)
  - Life: Japanese Study, 1968 (Offsite-box 4187, Folder 10)
  - London: Business, 1969-1970 (Offsite-box 4187, Folder 11)
  - London: Business, 1971-1972 (Offsite-box 4187, Folder 12)
  - London: Business, 1973 (Offsite-box 4187, Folder 13)
  - London: International Raise Review, 1972 (Offsite-box 4187, Folder 14)
  - London: International Raise Review, 1973 (Offsite-box 4187, Folder 15)
  - London: Personnel, 1969-1970 (Offsite-box 4187, Folder 16)
  - London: Personnel, 1971-1972 (Offsite-box 4187, Folder 17)
  - London: Personnel, 1973 (Offsite-box 4187, Folder 18)
  - Manilla: Miscellaneous, 1968 (Offsite-box 4187, Folder 19)
  - Manilla: Miscellaneous, 1969-1970 (Offsite-box 4187, Folder 20)
  - Middle East: General, 1967 (Offsite-box 4187, Folder 21)
  - Peru: Miscellaneous, 1968-1969 (Offsite-box 4187, Folder 22)
  - Philippines: Advertising, 1968-1970 (Offsite-box 4187, Folder 23)
  - Philippines: Circulation File, 1969 (Offsite-box 4187, Folder 24)
  - Philippines: Corporate and Legal Matters, 1968-1971 (Offsite-box 4187, Folder 25)
  - Philippines: Marcos vs. Time, 1971 (Offsite-box 4187, Folder 26)
  - Philippines: Time Life International Philippines (TLIP) Problems, 1971 (Offsite-box 4187, Folder 27)
  - South Africa: Miscellaneous, 1964 (Offsite-box 4188, Folder 1)
  - Sydney: Business, 1969-1970 (Offsite-box 4188, Folder 2)
  - Sydney: Business, 1969-1970 (Offsite-box 4188, Folder 3)
  - Sydney: Business, 1971-1972 (Offsite-box 4188, Folder 4)
  - Sydney: Personnel, 1969-1970 (Offsite-box 4188, Folder 5)
  - Sydney: Personnel, 1971-1972 (Offsite-box 4188, Folder 6)
  - Tokyo: Business, 1969-1970 (Offsite-box 4188, Folder 7)
  - Tokyo: Business, 1971 (Offsite-box 4188, Folder 8)
  - Tokyo: Business, 1972 (Offsite-box 4188, Folder 9)
  - Tokyo: Business, 1973 (Offsite-box 4188, Folder 10)
  - Tokyo: Incorporation, 1970-1971 (Offsite-box 4188, Folder 11)
  - Tokyo: Personnel, 1969-1970 (Offsite-box 4188, Folder 12)
  - Tokyo: Personnel, 1971 (Offsite-box 4188, Folder 13)
  - Tokyo: Personnel, 1972 (Offsite-box 4188, Folder 14)
  - Tokyo: Personnel, 1973 (Offsite-box 4188, Folder 15)
  - Tokyo: Personnel, 1973 (Offsite-box 4188, Folder 16)
  - Tokyo: Space Project, 1968 (Offsite-box 4188, Folder 17)
- Series II: Vice President Martin Gardner Files, 1984-1997; 5 Linear feet in 5 record cartons.
  Series II consists of correspondence, reports, projections, proposed projects, printed presentations, information on the state of publishing ventures, samples of magazines, and information about certain major advertisers. The materials were produced during Martin Gardner's role as Vice President of Time Inc. International and largely concerns review of and planning for Time Inc. International's business ventures.
  Series II is arranged alphabetically.
  - Acquisitions, 1991-1993 (Offsite-box 4190, Folder 1)
  - Acquisitions, 1993 (Offsite-box 4190, Folder 2)
  - Acquisitions [Restricted], 1991-1993 (Offsite-box R86)
  - Announcements, 1996-1997 (Offsite-box 4190, Folder 3)
  - April Estimates, 1997 (Offsite-box 4190, Folder 4)
  - Asia, 1996 (Offsite-box 4190, Folder 5-8)
  - Asia, 1996 (Offsite-box 4190, Folder 9)
  - Asia, 1996 (Offsite-box 4190, Folder 10)
  - Asia [Restricted], 1996 (Offsite-box R86)
  - Asia Inflight [empty], undated (Offsite-box 4190, Folder 11)
  - Atlantic (Atlo), 1996 (Offsite-box 4190, Folder 12-13)
  - Atlantic (Atlo), 1996 (Offsite-box 4190, Folder 14-15)
  - Atlantic (Atlo), 1996 (Offsite-box 4191, Folder 1-2)
  - Atlantic (Atlo), 1996 (Offsite-box 4191, Folder 3)
  - Cave, Roy, 1984-1987 (Offsite-box 4191, Folder 4)
  - Central 1996 Budget (Offsite-box 4191, Folder 5-6)
  - Central 1996 Budget (Offsite-box 4191, Folder 7)
  - Currency, 1996 (Offsite-box 4191, Folder 8)
  - Dancyu, 1996 (Offsite-box 4191, Folder 9)
  - Davidson Atai, 1996 (Offsite-box 4191, Folder 10)
  - Doder, undated (Offsite-box 4191, Folder 11)
  - Dow Corning, 1991 (Offsite-box 4191, Folder 12-14)
  - Edit Decentralization, 1996 (Offsite-box 4191, Folder 15-16)
  - Edit Decentralization Steer, 1996 (Offsite-box 4191, Folder 17)
  - Edit Decentralization Steer [Restricted], 1996 (Offsite-box R86)
  - Edit Positioning, 1991 (Offsite-box 4191, Folder 18)
  - Entertainment Weekly Japan, 1996 (Offsite-box 4192, Folder 1-2)
  - Europe, 1996 (Offsite-box 4192, Folder 3)
  - Europe, 1996 (Offsite-box 4192, Folder 4)
  - Expense Reports, 1984-1988 (Offsite-box 4192, Folder 5)
  - Expense Reports [Restricted], 1984 (Offsite-box R86)
  - Fortune European Roundtable, 1996 (Offsite-box 4192, Folder 6)
  - Globe Media, 1996 (Offsite-box 4192, Folder 7)
  - Independent Media Distribution (IMD), 1996-1997 (Offsite-box 4192, Folder 8)
  - Independent Media Distribution (IMD) Working File: Dealing with Hanbury, 1996 (Offsite-box 4192, Folder 9)
  - Independent Media Distribution (IMD) Working File: Dealing with Hanbury [Restricted], 1996 (Offsite-box R86)
  - Independent Media Distribution (IMD) Working File: Email, 1996-1997 (Offsite-box 4192, Folder 10)
  - Independent Media Distribution (IMD) Working File: General Files, 1996-1997 (Offsite-box 4192, Folder 11)
  - Independent Media Distribution (IMD) Working File: Hanbury's Approach to Logan, 1996-1997 (Offsite-box 4192, Folder 12)
  - International Circulation Conference Notes, 1996 (Offsite-box 4192, Folder 13)
  - International Circulation Conference Venue/Billing, 1996 (Offsite-box 4192, Folder 14)
  - International Finance Forum, 1996 (Offsite-box 4192, Folder 15)
  - John Buck Company, 1996 (Offsite-box 4192, Folder 16)
  - John Buck Company [Restricted], 1996 (Offsite-box R86)
  - Kleinwort Benson, 1991 (Offsite-box 4192, Folder 17-18)
  - Latin America (LatAm), 1996 (Offsite-box 4192, Folder 19)
  - Latin America (LatAm), 1996 (Offsite-box 4193, Folder 1)
  - Latin America (LatAm), 1996 (Offsite-box 4193, Folder 2)
  - Latin America (LatAm), 1996 (Offsite-box 4193, Folder 3)
  - Licensing: Magazines, 1990, 1993 (Offsite-box 4193, Folder 4)
  - Magazine Omnibus Study, 1993 (Offsite-box 4193, Folder 5)
  - Magazines: Business Presentation, 1996 (Offsite-box 4193, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1996 (Offsite-box 4193, Folder 7)
  - Murdoch Magazines, undated (Offsite-box 4193, Folder 8)
  - New Job, 1988-1990 (Offsite-box 4193, Folder 9)
  - New Job, 1984-1993 (Offsite-box 4193, Folder 10)
  - Olympics, 1996 (Offsite-box 4193, Folder 11)
  - Olympics '96: Meeting, 1996 (Offsite-box 4193, Folder 12)
  - Olympics '96: Meetings, 1996 (Offsite-box 4193, Folder 13)
  - People Japan, 1997 (Offsite-box 4193, Folder 14)
  - President, 1996 (Offsite-box 4193, Folder 15-16)
  - South Pacific (SOPAC), 1996-1997 (Offsite-box 4193, Folder 17)
  - South Pacific (SOPAC) Financial Review, 1996 (Offsite-box 4193, Folder 18)
  - Strategic Plan Meeting [empty], undated (Offsite-box 4193, Folder 19)
  - Time Canada, 1996 (Offsite-box 4193, Folder 20)
  - Time Inc. Europe Strategic Plan Review [empty], undated (Offsite-box 4193, Folder 21)
  - Time Inc. International 1996 Results, 1997 (Offsite-box 4193, Folder 22)
  - Time International Edit, 1989-1993 (Offsite-box 4194, Folder 1-4)
  - Travel and Leisure Europe: Development Ideas, 1992-1995 (Offsite-box 4194, Folder 5-8)
  - Who Weekly, 1997 (Offsite-box 4194, Folder 9)
  - Who Weekly, 1996 (Offsite-box 4194, Folder 10-14)
  - Zenith Media Worldwide, 1992 (Offsite-box 4194, Folder 15)
- Series III: Mike Taylor Files, 1997; 1 Linear feet in 1 record carton.
  Series III consists of correspondence, reports, budgets, and printed presentations produced in a review of the state of Time Inc. International's various business concerns and proposals for future development during Mike Taylor's time working for Time Inc in "strategic aspects of international magazine publishing".
  Series III is arranged alphabetically.
  - Ad Sales Reporting, 1997 (Offsite-box 4189, Folder 1)
  - Asiaweek: Financial Review, 1997 (Offsite-box 4189, Folder 2)
  - Budget Meetings, 1997 (Offsite-box 4189, Folder 3)
  - Budget Review, 1997 (Offsite-box 4189, Folder 4)
  - Financial Review and Budget Information, 1997 (Offsite-box 4189, Folder 5)
  - Income and Budgets, 1997 (Offsite-box 4189, Folder 6)
  - Information Re-Design, 1997 (Offsite-box 4189, Folder 7)
  - Legal Expenses, 1997 (Offsite-box 4189, Folder 8)
  - Reports, 1997 (Offsite-box 4189, Folder 9)
  - Special Issues, 1997 (Offsite-box 4189, Folder 10)
  - Time Asia, 1997 (Offsite-box 4189, Folder 11-12)
  - Time Atlantic, 1997 (Offsite-box 4189, Folder 13)
  - Time Inc. Australia, 1997 (Offsite-box 4189, Folder 14)
  - Time Inc. Australia: Financial Review, 1997 (Offsite-box 4189, Folder 15)
  - Time Inc. South Pacific (SOPAC), 1997 (Offsite-box 4189, Folder 16)